Guide to the Violet Hunt papers, 1858-1962.
Hunt, Violet papers, 1858-1962.
- Series I. Family
  - 1. Hunt family (Raine/Peacock/Hunt)
    - a. Correspondence
      - ii. General
        - Hook, James Clarke, 1819-1907. -- [n.d., 1867-1886] (Box 2, Folder 13-a-s)
          19 ASL's to Alfred William and Margaret Raine Hunt
          50 ll.
          Many with envelopes.
          Mostly concerned with payment of rent on 1 Tor Villa, Campden Hill. One letter is addressed to Alfred Hunt, the rest to Margaret Hunt.
        - Hunt, Alfred William, 1830-1896. -- [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 14-a)
          AL to [?]
          4 Normandy Terrace, Whitby Rhyparography I suppose means
        - Hunt, Alfred William, 1830-1896. -- Sept. 18 [1857] (Box 2, Folder 14-b-c)
          ALS to William Greenwell
          Conway Dear Greenwell I am in the land of/damp-
          Andrew Hunt is Alfred Hunt's father.
          With sketch of Corpus Christi College, Oxford, on front.
        - Hunt, Alfred William, 1830-1896. -- Nov. ? [1850s] (Box 2, Folder 14-d)
          ALS to Maria Hunt
          Oxford Dear Maria The simple reason why/I did not write to you last week
          Maria Hunt is Alfred Hunt's sister.
        - Hunt, Alfred William, 1830-1896. -- [1851] (Box 2, Folder 14-e)
          Oxford My dear Maria You see I have secured
        - Hunt, Alfred William, 1830-1896. -- Nov. 15 [1853] (Box 2, Folder 14-f)
          Oxford Dear Maria Have I not had a pleasant/birthday? today?
        - Hunt, Alfred William, 1830-1896. -- Sept. 18, 1859 (Box 2, Folder 14-g)
          Durham My dear Maria I am sorry that I was not/able
          2 ll. + 1, with envelope.
        - Hunt, William Holman, 1827-1910. -- Apr. 16-18 [n.y.] (Box 2, Folder 15)
          [printed ] S [invitation to view "Holman Hunt's Picture of Isabella or the Pot of Basil"]
          Invitation to admit Mrs. H. Hunt and friend to Messrs. E. Gambart & Cos. New Gallery, presumably sent to Mrs. Alfred Hunt and signed by W. Holman Hunt.
          With invitation to Margaret, Alfred, and Violet Hunt to visit the Holman Hunts at their home on March 6 [n.y.] affixed to the back.
        - Hutton, Richard H., The Spectator Office -- Oct. 27, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 16a-b)
          London My dear Mrs Hunt Certainly I am dead against
          With handwritten copy of the letter by Margaret Raine Hunt.
        - Kingsley, W. -- Sept. 2?, 1858 (Box 2, Folder 17)
          TL [copy ] S to Alfred William Hunt
          Capel Curig My dear Hunt I return you Ruskin's letter; as far as I see it
          Typed copy
        - Matthews, C. N. -- Thursday [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 18)
          15, Stanley Gardens, W. Dear Mrs. Hunt A telegram from/Pen Browning
          Giving news of Robert Browning's condition.
          Mrs. Matthews is the sister of Sir Frederick Leighton.
        - Moulton, Louise Chandler, 1835-1908. -- Dec. 14 [1899?] (Box 2, Folder 19)
          ALS to [Margaret Raine Hunt?]
          Boston My dear Friend of so/ many years -- I am/hurt at your treatment/of me,
        - Nash, E. Barrington -- Dec. 9, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 20)
          [printed] [invitation to view the Bartolozzi Exhibition]
          Addressed to the Hunt family.
        - Peacock, G. -- May 3, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 21)
          ALS to James Raine
          29 Old Elvet My dear James I write to you a few/lines
          With references to Margaret Raine Hunt and Alfred Hunt.
          James Raine was Margaret Raine Hunt's brother and G. Peacock was their aunt.
        - Peacock, George, 1791-1858. -- Nov. 22, 1827 (Box 2, Folder 22-a)
          ALS to [Margaret] Peacock Raine
          Lincoln College, Cambridge My dear Niece I have many apologies to make
          George Peacock was Margaret Peacock Raine's uncle, presumably the brother of her father, Thomas Peacock. Margaret Peacock Raine was Margaret Raine Hunt's mother and Violet Hunt's grandmother.
        - Peacock, George, 1791-1858. -- Dec. 15, 1856 (Box 2, Folder 22-b)
          Deanery, Ely My dear Midge It is an age since I have
          George Peacock was Margaret Raine Hunt's uncle and Dean of Ely.
        - Peacock, George, 1791-1858. -- Apr. 28, 1858 (Box 2, Folder 22-c)
          Union Hotel, Cockspar Sheet My dear Midge I shall be here soon/after 6
        - Peacock, George, 1791-1858. -- [Oct. 20, 1847] (Box 2, Folder 22-d)
          Calling card
          1 l. + 2
          With calling card of Mrs. Peacock and envlope addressed to "W. Peacock, 17 Park Terrace, Islington."
          George Peacock was the brother of Margaret Peacock Raine, Margaret Raine Hunt's mother and Violet Hunt's grandmother.
        - Peacock, Thomas -- Nov. 8, 1825 (Box 2, Folder 23)
          ALS to Hannah Peacock
          Denton My dear Hannah, Herewith I send you
        - Pfeiffer, Mrs. -- [May 15, 1888] (Box 2, Folder 24)
          [printed] [invitation to visit]
          Addressed to Margaret Raine Hunt.
        - Raine family -- [n.d.], 1798-1841 (Box 2, Folder 25-a-p)
          16 envelopes
          16 ll.
          Envelopes addressed to members of Margaret Raine Hunt's family, including George Peacock, James Raine, and Mrs. Raine, as well as various other recipients. One envelope, addressed to Benjamin Dorkray, is supposedly in William Wordsworth's handwriting.
        - Raine, James, 1791-1858. -- [19th century] (Box 2, Folder 26-a-b)
          Foreign postcards and envelope
          Five foreign postcards and one envelope attached to a sheet of paper, the envelope being addressed to James Raine, Margaret Raine Hunt's father. One of the postcards is written in Japanese, one in French, two in Hindi, and one in Arabic. There is also an unattached piece of Japanese currency.
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- [1856?] (Box 2, Folder 27-a)
          TL [copy] to Alfred William Hunt
          [n.p.] Dear Hunt I've been noticing that row for a long time
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- [1862] (Box 2, Folder 27-b)
          Denmark Hill My dear Hunt. I want to tell you how much
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- May 25, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 27-c)
          Northwich My dear Hunt. I shall have the greatest pleasure
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- June 20, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 27-d)
          AL [copy] & TL [copy] to Alfred William Hunt
          Denmark Hill My dear Hunt, I saw your two pictures on Saturday
          Handwritten copy made by Margaret Hunt.
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- June 24, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 27-e)
          AL [copy] to Alfred William Hunt
          [n.p.] My dear Hunt I have your nice letter and am
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Aug. 12, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 27-f)
          [n.p.] My dear Hunt I shall have a deep pleasure
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- July 31, 1866 (Box 2, Folder 27-g)
          Denmark Hill My dear Hunt For many reasons,--too many to be
          Handwritten copy by Margaret Hunt.
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Feb. 2, 1867 (Box 2, Folder 27-h)
          Denmark Hill, S.E. My dear Hunt I have chosen/Near Arundel
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Mar. 20, 1868 (Box 2, Folder 27-i)
          Denmark Hill Dear Hunt Is there any day next week
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- [1873] (Box 2, Folder 27-j)
          Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire Dear Hunt I return you the papers, in case
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Jan. 6, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 27-k)
          Brantwood, Coniston My dear Hunt I cannot conceive a fitter person for that professorship
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- May 19, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 27-l)
          Corpus Christi College, Oxford My dear Alfred, I couldn't write sooner -
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- [May 21, 1873] (Box 2, Folder 27-m)
          Corpus Christi College, Oxford My dear Alfred. It is a great joy to me
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- June 16, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 27-n)
          Herne Hill Dear Hunt I am so glad of your pretty letter.
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- July 19 [1873] (Box 2, Folder 27-o)
          My dear Alfred You will I doubt not hear from Margaret
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Oct. 22 [1873] (Box 2, Folder 27-p)
          Brantwood, Coniston Dear Hunt I shall be delighted to see you and
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Nov. 6, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 27-q)
          Corpus Christi College, Oxford My dear Hunt It is a great comfort to me to have this letter
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Nov. 28, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 27-r)
          Oxford My dear Hunt I am very conceited about my sketches being placed,
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Jan. 5, 1874 (Box 2, Folder 27-s)
          Herne Hill Dear Hunt Best thanks for nice letter, and
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Nov. 24, 1874 (Box 2, Folder 27-t)
          Corpus Christi College [Oxford] My dear Hunt I am very glad and proud of your letter
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Feb. 21, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 27-u)
          Brantwood My dear Hunt Your letter has just come to me and though today jaded
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Apr. 25, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 27-v)
          Newark My dear Alfred I have heard from Mr Oliver
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Apr. 20, 1880 (Box 2, Folder 27-v)
          Envelope addressed to Alfred William Hunt
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Nov. 10, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 27-w)
          Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire My dear Alfred I am so very grateful for your letter
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Apr. 20, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 27-x)
          Brantwood, Coniston Dear Hunt I am so very glad of your letter and report
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900 -- Mar. 30, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 27-y)
          L [printed] to [Alfred Hunt]
          Brantwood, Coniston Mr. Ruskin trusts that his friends will/pardon
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 28-a)
          TL [copy] to Margaret Raine Hunt
          Denmark Hill, S.E. Dear Mrs Hunt I am so grateful for the bird extracts
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Jan. 2, 1858 (Box 2, Folder 28-b)
          [n.p.] Dear Miss Raine. I should have replied to your kind letter
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Apr. 28, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 28-c)
          Northwich Dear Mrs Hunt. I am so grateful to you for remembering me
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Apr. 8, 1867 (Box 2, Folder 28-d)
          Denmark Hill, S. Dear Mrs Hunt I was so glad to have
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Nov. 10, 1867 (Box 2, Folder 28-e)
          Denmark Hill, S. Dear Mrs Hunt. I am sincerely vexed at my carelessness
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Dec. 18, 1868 (Box 2, Folder 28-f)
          Denmark Hill, S.E. Dear Mrs Hunt, Yes, it's all very fine but there are no photographs
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Dec. 18 [1868] (Box 2, Folder 28-g)
          AL [copy] to Margaret Raine Hunt
          Denmark Hill, S.E. Dear Mrs Hunt I am going to do what I would only do
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Dec. 18, 1868 (Box 2, Folder 28-h)
          Denmark Hill Dear Mrs Hunt I am more and more glad selfishly that I kept Joanna
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Feb. 5, 1869 (Box 2, Folder 28-i)
          Denmark Hill Dear Mrs Hunt Thank you for kind note, and
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Oct. 27, 1869 (Box 2, Folder 28-j)
          Denmark Hill My dear Mrs Hunt. Thank you so much for your letter, and for all
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Feb. 19, 1870 (Box 2, Folder 28-k)
          Corpus Christi College, Oxford My dear Margaret I have just opened your letter
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Feb. 8, 1871 (Box 2, Folder 28-l)
          Denmark Hill, S.E. Dear Mrs Hunt I hope your letter has not been lying here long
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- June 22, 1871 (Box 2, Folder 28-m)
          Denmark Hill, S.E. Dear Mrs Hunt, I have been, and am, wearily, and more or less,
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- [1872] (Box 2, Folder 28-n)
          Corpus Christi College, Oxford My dear Margaret I am quite beaten down with over-work
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Jan. 26, 1872 (Box 2, Folder 28-o)
          Denmark Hill, S.E. Dear Mrs Hunt The Photographs are safe, but I must not/see you
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Feb. 19, 1872 (Box 2, Folder 28-p)
          [n.p.] Dear Mrs Hunt So many thanks for your letter
          Handwritten copy made by Margaret Raine.
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Sept. 4, 1872 (Box 2, Folder 28-q)
          Brantwood, Coniston Dear Mrs Hunt I am more than glad to hear of Alfred
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Sept. 9, 1872 (Box 2, Folder 28-r)
          Brantwood, Coniston Dear Mrs Hunt The passage about the rainbow
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- [1873] (Box 2, Folder 28-s)
          Brantwood, Coniston Dear Margaret I was very grateful for your letter - I am sure Violet
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- [1873] (Box 2, Folder 28-t)
          Brantwood, Coniston My dear Margaret. It has been as unlucky for you that I have been busy
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Mar. 15, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 28-u)
          Corpus Christi College, Oxford Dear Mrs Hunt The indices are to be all together
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Apr. 2, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 28-v)
          Brantwood, Coniston Dear Mrs Hunt I cannot judge of the quality of the index
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- June 10, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 28-w)
          Herne Hill My dear Margaret I go up quite comfortably, and am happy in thinking
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- [July 26, 1873] (Box 2, Folder 28-x)
          Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire My dear Margaret. I was very sorry, as you must have seen
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Sept. 3, 1873? (Box 2, Folder 28-y)
          Herne Hill, S.E. My dear Mrs Hunt We were so sorry to hear Mr Hunt's not being well
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Dec. 16, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 28-z)
          London My dear Margaret I am very glad of your letter, and Alfred's gift
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Dec. 26, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 28-aa)
          London My dear Margaret. Your letter gives me the most
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Mar. 1, 1874 (Box 2, Folder 28-bb)
          Ambleside My dear Margaret I am very glad of your letter. What a wonderful speech
          With typed note about suicidal impulses in children.
          Typed copy.
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Dec. 23 [1874] (Box 2, Folder 28-cc)
          Corpus Christi College, Oxford Dear Mrs Hunt Are you and the children in town? )
          Misdated 1872.
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Feb. 11, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 28-dd)
          Oxford Dear Mrs Hunt, I am very thankful for your letter.
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Feb. 20, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 28-ee)
          Corpus Christi College, Oxford My dear Margaret That is in a way comforting!
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Feb. 24, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 28-ff)
          Corpus Christi College, Oxford My dear Margaret I really think Violets must be nicer than Roses after all
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Mar. 16, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 28-gg)
          London My dear Margaret It is gladness to me to hear
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- May 30, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 28-hh)
          Corpus Christi College, Oxford My dear Margaret I am very grateful for your letter. Yes, it
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- June 5, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 28-ii)
          Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire My dear Margaret I was very glad your were able to refer
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Sept. 2 [1875-1876?] (Box 2, Folder 28-jj)
          [n.p.] My dear Mrs Hunt Your generous letter has been to long
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- [1876] (Box 2, Folder 28-kk)
          Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire My dear Margaret. If good fathers and mothers always had
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Jan. 8, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 28-ll)
          Arundel My dear Margaret All very happy days are by gone, but we
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Feb. 19, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 28-mm)
          Corpus Christi College, Oxford My dear Margaret, I did not think my letter would have
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Mar. 25, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 28-nn)
          Corpus Christi College, Oxford My dear Margaret I like those poems of Violet's
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Jan. 25, 1877 (Box 2, Folder 28-oo)
          Venice My dear Margaret Though I have sent messages in Venice's letter
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Aug. 27, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 28-pp)
          Brantwood, Coniston My dear Margaret I got the "Hazard of the Die"
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Sept. 9, 1878 (Box 2, Folder 28-qq)
          Brantwood, Coniston My dear Margaret You must always remember that your novel
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- May 29, 1879 (Box 2, Folder 28-rr)
          Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire My dear Margaret I was still very weak when I last wrote
        - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900. -- Mar. 22, 1880 (Box 2, Folder 28-ss)
          London Dear Margaret So many thanks. They are lovely.
        - Safford, S. Sutherland -- Apr. 1887 (Box 2, Folder 29)
          AL [frag.] S to Alfred William Hunt
          [n.p.] ...to increase its sphere of/usefulness.
        - Scott, William Bell, 1811-1890. -- [Feb. 8, 1868] (Box 2, Folder 30-a)
          33 Elgin Road My Dear Hunt I hope you will let/me
        - Scott, William Bell, 1811-1890. -- [Oct. 16, 1867] (Box 2, Folder 30-b)
          33 Elgin Road My Dear Mrs Hunt Will you kindly/come
        - Scott, William Bell, 1811-1890. -- Nov. 26, 1871 (Box 2, Folder 30-c)
          Chelsea My Dear Mrs Hunt I have had it in/my conscience
        - Scott, William Bell, 1811-1890. -- Dec. 4, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 30-d)
          Chelsea My Dear Mrs Hunt You say in your/note just
        - Scott, William Bell, 1811-1890. -- Dec. 9, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 30-e)
          Chelsea My Dear Mrs Hunt I have read the/reviews, and I
        - Scott, William Bell, 1811-1890. -- Apr. 14, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 30-f)
          Chelsea My Dear Mrs Hunt Your Violet's poetry/is the greatest pleasure
        - Scott, William Bell, 1811-1890. -- Nov. 11, 1878 92 (Box 2, Folder 30-g)
          Cheyne Walk, S.W. My Dear Mrs Hunt I can't quite determine the/amount
        - Scott, William Bell, 1811-1890. -- Dec. 4, 1878 92 (Box 2, Folder 30-h)
          Cheyne Walk, S.W. Dear Mrs Hunt I have just finished/reading your
        - Scott, William Bell, 1811-1890. -- Nov. 27, 1880 92 (Box 2, Folder 30-i)
          Cheyne Walk, S.W. My Dear Mrs Hunt Very many thanks for/your two notes
        - Scott, William Bell, 1811-1890. -- May 21, 1885 92 (Box 2, Folder 30-j)
          Cheyne Walk, S.W. My Dear Mrs Hunt It was very kind of you
        - Scott, William Bell, 1811-1890. -- Aug. 12, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 30-k)
          Ayrshire My Dear Mrs Hunt A thousand thanks for/keeping me in mind.
        - Scott, William Bell, 1811-1890. -- Apr. 9, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 30-l)
          Ayrshire My Dear Mrs Hunt I was delighted to get your/note
        - Scott, William Bell, 1811-1890. -- Aug. 14, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 30-m)
          Ayrshire My Dear Mrs Hunt I write you a few lines--
        - Severn, Arthur -- [1872-1873] (Box 3, Folder 1-a)
          Brantwood My dear Mrs Hunt Thank you very much for your long
        - Severn, Joan Ruskin -- Thursday evening [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 1-b)
          Brantwood, Coniston Dear Mrs Hunt It is a fact that "the Coz" sent in his resignation
        - Severn, Joan Ruskin -- Saturday night [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 1-c)
          Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire My dear Mrs Hunt Since I wrote/yesterday things
        - Severn, Joan Ruskin -- [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 1-d)
          Brantwood, Coniston Lake, R.S.O. Dear Mrs Hunt In a letter to me/from Mr. Spielmann
        - Severn, Joan Ruskin -- May 14 [n.y.] (Box 3, Folder 1-e)
          Brantwood My dear Mrs Hunt Your most/interesting letter
        - Severn, Joan Ruskin -- Monday [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 1-f)
          Brantwood, Coniston, Lancashire My dear Mrs Hunt It is alas the/same sad illness
          1 l. + 1)
          With newspaper clipping concerning Joan Severn. Two photocopies of clipping included.
        - Sheed, W. -- Jan. 11, 1878 (Box 3, Folder 2)
          Campden Lodge Dear Sir I must beg you/to excuse me
        - Temple, W. Cowper -- June 10, 1878 (Box 3, Folder 3)
          15, Great Stanhope Street, W. Dear Sir - I have the/pleasure of
        - Tyrwhitt, R. St. John -- May 4, 1878 (Box 3, Folder 4-a)
          Ketilby, Oxford My dear Hunt Will you kindly excuse me to Mrs/Hunt for not answering her
          2 ll
        - Tyrwhitt, R. St. John -- May 15, 1878 (Box 3, Folder 4-b)
          Oxford Dear Mrs Hunt I send two more small/sums
          2 ll. With reference to John Ruskin.
        - Tyrwhitt, R. St. John -- May 22, 1878 (Box 3, Folder 4-c)
          Ketilby Dear Mrs Hunt Forgive a distracted divine
        - Tyrwhitt, R. St. John -- Jan. 22, 1879 (Box 3, Folder 4-d)
          Ketilby, Oxford Dear Mrs Hunt, I do not think Ruskin has resigned, though he wrote
        - Webster, Thomas -- Oct. 23, 1889 (Box 3, Folder 5)
          3, Howard Street, Strand Dear Mrs Hunt, Fogg Elliot/You will be anxious to know
    - b. Manuscripts
      - AM [Ruskin meets Mr. & Mrs. Cowper] -- [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 6)
        The friend who recounts the incident is unnamed and "private" is written at the top of the first page.
      - Elliot, John -- Apr. 17, 1676 AM (Box 3, Folder 7)
        [description of land]
      - Hunt family -- 1890-1895 (Box 3, Folder 8-a-g)
        TM & AM Diary
        7 ll
        With columns for Alfred, Margaret, Violet, Venice and Silvia Hunt and an additional column for other important events.
        With annotations in Violet Hunt's hand.
      - Hunt, Alfred William, 1830-1896. -- 1865-1876 (Box 3, Folder 9)
        AM Bankbook
        44 ll. + 1
        Volume with green cover.
      - Hunt, Alfred William, 1830-1896. -- [after 1906] (Box 3, Folder 10)
        [frag.] [printed] & AM [catalogue of paintings for sale]
        The pages with Hunt's paintings on them have been torn out and the prices they brought written in.
      - Hunt, Alfred William, 1830-1896. -- [1836-1893] (Box 3, Folder 11)
        AM Notebook with details of Hunt's pictures
        75 ll. + 1 + 1
        Provides title and remarks, price, place, and date.
        With back cover of volume and one loose sheet; last leaf pasted to back cover.
      - Hunt, Alfred William, 1830-1896. -- 1863-1864 (Box 3, Folder 12)
        AMS [init.] "What will your last words be, my Margaret?"-[poem]
      - Hunt, Margaret Raine, 1831-1912. -- [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 13-a-b)
        AM Brief explanation
        Concerning John Ruskin.
      - Hunt, Margaret Raine, 1831-1912. -- [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 14-a-b)
        AM [Canon William Greenwell's character]
        Canon William Greenwell was Violet's godfather and Margaret's spurned suitor. Recounts an incident in which Violet fell into the water as a young child. Written over a printed ladies fashion adverstisement.
      - Hunt, Margaret Raine, 1831-1912. -- 1856 (Box 3, Folder 15)
        AM Receipt book
        148 ll. + 1
        Volume with marbled board and leather cover.
        With an index of recipes at the end.
      - Raine, James, 1791-1858. -- Apr. 28 -December 1858 (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
        TM & AM [unfinished autobiography]
        246 ll.
        Two copies of both the autobiography and the additional typed notes, including some annotations and notes, probably by Violet and Margaret Raine Hunt.